osh.com 2017-12-12

# Privacy Policy | Orchard Supply Hardware Store

## Orchard Supply Hardware Privacy Statement

#### **Effective on April 20, 2015**

Orchard Supply Company, LLC ("Orchard Supply Hardware", “our" or "we"), a subsidiary of Lowe’s Companies, Inc., respects your privacy. This Privacy Statement describes how we collect, use, share, and protect information, and the choices you can make about such information. It also contains other important privacy disclosures, such as how we may update the Statement and how you can contact us. This Privacy Statement applies to most interactions with our customers, visitors, and online job applicants, including:

  * Use of our websites that point to this Statement;
  * Phone, e-mail, and other electronic or written communications;
  * Visits to our stores or other in-person events;
  * Social media interactions;
  * Surveys, contests, and sweepstakes; and
  * Online Advertisements

In some cases, we may provide additional details about privacy practices specific to a particular operation or location. For example, some stores may post additional privacy details specific to that store or an event.

**
    * INFORMATION WE COLLECT
    * Information You Provide
    * Information We Collect by Automated Means Online
    * Information We Collect by Automated Means Offline Credit cards accepted for online orders
    * Information We Collect from Other Sources
    * HOW WE USE INFORMATION
    * HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION 
    * Service Providers 
    * Legal, Enforcement, Security, and Investigation
    * Sale or Transfer of Business or Assets
    * Aggregate or De-Identified Data
    * HOW WE PROTECT INFORMATION 
    * YOUR INFORMATION CHOICES
    * Club Orchard
    * Postal Mail & E-Mail
    * Interest-Based Advertising
    * OTHER IMPORTANT CONSIDERATIONS
    * Do Not Track
    * Interest-Based Advertising
    * Social Media Widgets
    * Links to Other Websites
    * Information Collected by Third Parties
    * Children
    * Notice to California Customers 
    * Updates
    * How to Contact Us
** 

### Information We Collect

We may collect information that identifies you or that is associated with you in a number of ways, including information you provide to us, information we automatically collect, and information we obtain from third parties.

#### Information You Provide

You may choose to provide us with information. Examples include:

  * Contact and identification information, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, driver’s license number, date of birth, and social security number;
  * Payment information, such as your payment card number and expiration date, or gift card information;
  * Demographic information, such as your age, gender, income range, and occupation;
  * Login and access credentials, such as your username and password for your OSH.com and Club Orchard accounts, or social media IDs;
  * Information about your purchases, returns, and exchanges, including warranty and rebate information;
  * Information you include in your communications with us or in connection with a satisfaction survey;
  * Content you submit, such as photographs, product reviews, and details about your projects and property; and
  * Information you submit in connection with a job application, including the types of information described above, plus other examples like employment status, employment history, education information, references, résumé, immigration status and ability to work legally in the United States, personal or family employment affiliation, criminal record, and, on a voluntary basis, for our Equal Employment Opportunity compliance purposes for jobs located in the US, gender, race and ethnic background.

#### Information We Collect by Automated Means Online

When you use our websites (“online services”), we may collect certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, Web server logs, and Web beacons. This information may be used to provide a better-tailored shopping experience, and for market research, data analytics, and system administration purposes. For instance, we may use this information to determine whether you've visited us before or are new to our website, to store your preferences and settings, to provide sign-in authentication, and for compliance with our legal obligations, policies, and procedures. We also may use this information to target custom content and ads to you on this and other websites, including as described in the Interest-Based Advertising section below.

Our online services may use cookies and other types of local storage (such as browser-based or plugin-based local storage). Cookies are small text files that websites send to your computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify your browser or to store information or settings. Your browser may provide the ability to notify you when you receive certain types of cookies and the ability to restrict or disable certain cookies.

Our online services generally use Web server logs to record information about your use of the services, such as your device type, operating system type, browser type, domain, system settings, and IP address, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone where your device is located. These logs also may record information such as the address of the Web page that referred you to our website, and other information about your interaction with our websites, such as which pages you visit. This is a common practice that supports the operation of our online services.

Our web pages, e-mails, and electronic newsletters may contain tags known as “Web beacons” or “single-pixel gifs,” which are small electronic images used to help deliver cookies on our sites, count visitors to our webpages, determine whether e-mails are opened, and deliver co-branded services. We may also work with other companies by sharing information about the use of our beacons or to place Web beacons on our sites, their sites, in our e-mails, or in advertisements, to let us develop statistics on how often clicking on an advertisement or product on our sites or in our e-mails results in a purchase or other action, including on other sites. Our webpages and e-mails may also contain Web beacons from third parties, which help us compile aggregated statistics regarding the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns or other website operations. These Web beacons may allow the third parties to set or read a cookie on your computer.

We may also use third-party Web analytics services in our online services, such as those of Google Analytics. These service providers help us analyze how users use our online services. Information collected as a part of Google Analytics (including your IP address) is automatically sent to Google, and Google may place cookies to help with the analysis. To learn more about Google Analytics and download an opt-out browser add-on, please click[ **here**](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

#### Information We Collect by Automated Means Offline

When you call our customer service centers or other phone support lines, we may record audio of the conversations for quality control, training, security, and analytics purposes.

We use video monitoring and recording at our stores to enhance security, protect against theft and other crimes, and to monitor in-store traffic patterns, customer counts and interests, and perform similar analytics.

In some stores, we may use OSHbot robots to enhance the customer service experience. The OSHbot uses a touch screen along with visual and voice sensors to interact with customers, provide product information, and help customers find the products they are looking for. The OSHbot does not collect personal information and its sensors do not collect or store information intended to allow identification of individuals.

#### Information We Collect from Other Sources

We may obtain certain information about you from other businesses, such as updated addresses or phone numbers we obtain from vendors who maintain such data, or your e-mail address if you have “opted in” with them to receive marketing communications from Orchard Supply Hardware. We may also obtain information about you from individuals, such as through “Refer a Friend” programs or if someone purchases a product and asks that it be delivered to you, and from public sources, such as information you submit in a public forum (for example, a customer review).

### HOW WE USE INFORMATION

We may use the information we collect for a range of business purposes, including to:

  * Provide and deliver products and services and fulfill your orders;
  * Process, record, and track your purchases, payments, returns, warranties, and rebates;
  * Communicate with you through various channels;
  * Evaluate and respond to your requests, inquiries, and applications;
  * Create and manage your account registrations, such as your OSH.com and Club Orchard accounts;
  * Conduct and administer contests, surveys, and sweepstakes;
  * Customize your experiences in our stores and online, including customized advertisements and offers;
  * Publish public product reviews as submitted by you and other customers;
  * Provide you with in-store navigation and mapping services and help you find store locations near you;
  * With respect to information we collect through our Careers website, evaluate your application for employment and contact you regarding possible employment;
  * Operate, evaluate, and improve our business, products, and services (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; performing market research, and data analytics; determining and managing the effectiveness of our advertising and marketing; analyzing our products, services, and websites; administer our websites; and perform accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities);
  * Protect against and prevent fraud and unauthorized transactions, investigate and manage claims, risk exposure, and quality, and generally improve and provide security; and
  * Comply with and enforce applicable legal requirements, industry standards, and our policies and terms, such as our[ **Terms of Use**](https://www.osh.com/terms).

### HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer personally identifiable information to unaffiliated third parties without your consent, except as described below.

#### Service Providers

We may disclose your personal information to companies that provide services to us (such as providers of hosting, support, delivery, printing, e-mail, data enhancement, and repair services) or that help us market our products and services. These companies may need access to information about you in order to perform their functions. These companies are not authorized to use the information we disclose to them for any other purpose.

When you request installed home improvement services, we may disclose the information you provide in the contact form you fill out online, or by calling our toll free number, to an authorized contractor so that they can contact you for a consultation and estimate. Similarly, if you choose to apply for an Orchard Business Credit Card provided by Synchrony Bank, we urge you to mail the application directly to Synchrony Bank. But if we receive a completed application, we will forward it to Synchrony Bank on your behalf.

#### Legal, Enforcement, Security, and Investigation

We may disclose information about you (1) if we believe we are required to do so by law, regulation or legal process, such as a court order or subpoena; (2) as we deem appropriate or necessary in response to requests by government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities or tax authorities; (3) when we believe disclosure is appropriate or necessary to protect the rights, property, or safety of Orchard Supply Hardware, our customers, or others, including to prevent physical, financial or other harm, injury or loss, or to collect debt you owe; or (4) in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual unlawful activity.

#### Sale or Transfer of Business or Assets

We reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including, without limitation, in the event of a reorganization, dissolution, or liquidation).

#### Aggregate or De-Identified Data

We may share or make public aggregate or de-identified data derived from personally identifiable information. Such information, however, will not identify you or any other individual.

### HOW WE PROTECT INFORMATION

We maintain administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed and intended to protect personal information against accidental, unlawful, or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. Despite these safeguards, due to inherent uncertainty in the use of the Internet and information systems and the potential for unlawful attacks by third parties, we cannot guarantee that the use of our systems or websites will be completely safe or secure.

Information we collect and use may be transferred, stored, and accessed globally to support our operations. We retain information for as long as it is needed or useful to provide and improve our products and services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### YOUR INFORMATION CHOICES

#### Club Orchard

If you are a member of Club Orchard, you may log into your account at www.cluborchard.osh.com at any time and modify or update your information and/or cancel your membership. You can also contact us at 888-SHOP-OSH (888-746-7674) and select option 4 to speak to a Club Orchard representative.

#### Postal Mail & E-Mail

If you do not wish to receive mailers, coupons, and other promotional mail, you may contact us as indicated below. Please provide the mailing address you wish to exclude in your correspondence.

If you do not wish to continue to receive promotional and marketing e-mails, and you have registered for an account on osh.com, you may log into your account at any time and change your e-mail subscription preferences. Additionally, you may click on the "Unsubscribe" link in any promotional email you receive from us and update your preferences on the resulting webpage. You may also contact us as indicated below. Please note that due to e-mail production schedules you may still receive any e-mails already in production but not yet sent.

We may also continue to send transactional e-mails, which contain information about a prior purchase or an ongoing service, even if you opt-out of promotional e-mails or newsletters.

Contact Information:  
Orchard Supply Hardware  
Privacy Office  
6450 Via Del Oro  
San Jose, CA 95119  
408-281-3500  

#### Interest-Based Advertising

To exercise your preferences regarding the collection and use of data for online, interest-based advertising, please follow the directions in the Interest-Based Advertising section below.

### OTHER IMPORTANT CONSIDERATIONS

#### Do Not Track

We do not collect personally identifiable information about users’ online activities over time and across third-party websites and we do not process or respond to "Do Not Track" signals from your browser or other mechanisms that enable consumer choice regarding the collection of personal information about one's online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services.

As described in the Interest-Based Advertising section below, however, we do participate in online advertising networks administered by third parties, and we may share information about activities on our websites with those networks, which may track your online activities over time and across third-party websites.

#### Interest-Based Advertising

We collect data about your activities on our websites for use in providing advertising tailored to your individual interests, and we may share information about activities on our websites with advertising networks administered by third parties. These ad networks track your online activities over time and across websites by collecting information through automated means, and they use this information to show you advertisements that are tailored to your individual interests. The information they collect includes information about your visits to our websites, such as the pages you have viewed. This collection and ad targeting takes place both on our websites and on third-party websites that participate in the ad network, such as sites that feature advertisements delivered by the ad network. As a result, you may see certain ads on other websites based on prior activity on our websites.

The Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) has created guidance for online advertisers and provided a mechanism for such advertisers to comply with users’ choices regarding interest-based ads. To learn more about ad networks, including how to opt out of interest-based ads, click[ **here**](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

#### Social Media Widgets

Our online services may include social media features (for example, a Facebook “Like” button). These features are connected to third-parties and may allow such third parties to collect certain information, such as your IP address and which pages you visit on our websites. These social media features are not operated by Orchard Supply Hardware. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policies of the company providing the features.

#### Links to Other Websites

Our online services may link to other websites for your convenience and information. For instance, they may link to websites of product suppliers, manufacturers, and service providers. These websites may be operated by companies not affiliated with us. Linked websites may have their own privacy notices, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit them. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of any website that we do not control and that does not point to this Privacy Statement. Your interactions with these websites are governed by the privacy policies of the company operating the websites.

#### Information Collected by Third Parties

To provide you with increased value, we may allow third-parties to offer products through kiosks located in our stores, or refer you to third parties for decorating or similar services. These third parties have separate and independent privacy policies, or may have no privacy policy. We are not responsible for the activities or privacy practices of such third parties.

#### Children

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, we ask that a parent or guardian contact us so that the information can be deleted.

#### Notice to California Customers

Subject to certain limitations under California Civil Code § 1798.83, if you are a California resident and have an established business relationship with us, you may ask us to provide you with (i) a list of certain categories of personal information that we have disclosed to certain third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year and (ii) the identity of certain third parties that received personal information from us for their direct marketing purposes during that calendar year. To make such a request, please contact us as follows:

Orchard Supply Hardware  
Privacy Office  
6450 Via Del Oro  
San Jose, CA 95119

We do not disclose personal information to third parties, including subsidiaries or corporate affiliates, for their direct marketing purposes.

#### Updates

This Privacy Statement may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our information practices or relevant laws. We will post a notice on OSH.com and other websites that point to this Privacy Statement to notify you of any substantive changes to the way we collect and use information. We will indicate at the top of the Privacy Statement when it was last updated.

#### How to Contact Us

If you have questions or comments about this Privacy Statement or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us as indicated below.

Orchard Supply Hardware  
Privacy Office  
6450 Via Del Oro  
San Jose, CA 95119  
408-281-3500
